Privacy Policy
==============

### **Opt Out**

You can choose to decline the web-based tracking features by visiting our opt-out page on your mobile web browser:

### **The privacy policy of the LiquidM Technology GmbH in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

This Privacy Policy applies to the web services and websites of  LiquidM Technology GmbH, Invalidenstr. 74, 10557 Berlin, Germany, represented by Philipp Simon and Thomas Hille, hereinafter referred to as LiquidM. “This Privacy Policy is always to be regarded as part of the respective web presence which directly refers to this site (e.g. under “Privacy” or “Privacy Policy”).

As a controller in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), LiquidM takes the protection of your personal data very seriously. We would like to inform you about when we collect what data and how we use it. We have implemented extensive technical and organizational measures (Art. 32 GDPR) to ensure compliance with and adherence to applicable provisions on data protection and data security by LiquidM and as well contracted third party providers. Please note that amendments to this Privacy Policy may be required due to the ongoing development of our websites and the implementation of new technologies to improve our web services. We, therefore, recommend frequently referring back to this Privacy Policy and reading through the current up-to-date version, which is always available online under [https://www.liquidm.com/privacy-policy](https://liquidm.com/privacy-policy/).

**I. WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

According to Art.4 No. 1 GDPR, personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, therefore can be used to obtain personal or factual details about the data subject (such as name, address, telephone number, date of birth or e-mail address). Information that cannot (directly or indirectly) be associated with a natural person (or only with disproportionate effort), for example, anonymous information, is not personal information.

**II. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND PROCESS?**

You can use a portion of our online content without providing personal information.

**a) Contact forms**

If you, however, decide to request further information via the contact forms provided on our website, we may ask for your name and further personal information in order to handle your personal request or to provide the services you requested from us or our customers. You can freely decide whether or not you want to provide that information. However, without this information, we are unable to make the desired services available to you.

**b) User account (LiquidM Platform)**

Certain services of our Online-Service called “LiquidM Platform” with which you can create and display advertising campaigns on your own, upload list of advertising IDs for retargeting campaigns and specify targeting criteria for your campaigns, can only be used by registered users with a user account. We store your e-mail address during registration. The e-mail address serves as a username to identify your member account, and to conduct relevant correspondence with you (e.g. setting up and maintaining your user account). As part of the registration process, we also collect your first and last name, your salutation and information about your company affiliation, mailing address, to ensure that you receive personalized, competent service. All mandatory information required in order to register is marked accordingly. All further information is provided voluntarily; this data is used for the purposes stated, or to improve our online services.

By registering with our websites, you declare your agreement with the [General Terms and Conditions](https://liquidm.com/general-terms-conditions/) of LiquidM and the use of your abovementioned personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you wish to register as a user of our LiquidM App and open a user account, please select for your own safety a secret and secure password in order to ensure the confidentiality of your data. Your password is transmitted to and stored on our servers in encrypted form, in the event that you forget your password, please use the “Forgot your password?” function provided on the website to create a new, secure password.

If you want to delete your account, please contact us at info@liquidm.com. If deletion is not possible for legal reasons, access to the data in question shall instead be blocked. Please note, however, that we may be unable to continue offering some or all of the services provided on our websites requiring registration in the event that your data is deleted or blocked.

**c) LiquidM newsletter**

As part of our web services, we offer a regular subscription to our LiquidM newsletter. When requested, the newsletter provides you with free, up-to-date information on our services. To register without LiquidM newsletter service, we need your first and last name, your gender, and the e-mail address at which you wish to receive the newsletter. If you wish to subscribe to the LiquidM newsletter, we ask that you provide us with the following declaration of consent:

_I would like to regularly receive the LiquidM newsletter and agree that my e-mail address, my first and last name, and my gender, as well as any data voluntarily provided, be used for this purpose. I can revoke this declaration of consent at any time by using the “Opt-Out function” in the respective LiquidM Newsletter or via an e-mail notice to [newsletter@liquidm.com](mailto:newsletter@liquidm.com), as well as by writing to LiquidM GmbH, Invalidenstr. 74,_ _10557_ _Berlin, Germany, such revocation to take effect for the future. No additional fees beyond the normal transmission fees of my e-mail or Internet provider shall apply. In the event that my consent is revoked, I shall not, or shall no longer, be able to receive the LiquidM newsletter. I have read and accepted the current privacy policy._

**III. DELIVERY OF PERSONALISED OR BEHAVIOUR-BASED ADVERTISING (BEHAVIORAL TARGETING)**

In certain cases, we showcase advertising to you on the websites of our partners and for our customers, which are automatically selected on the basis of your surfing behaviour, in order to optimise the quality of the advertising notices for you (so-called “personalised” or “behaviour-based” advertising delivery and “behavioral targeting”). The objective of this system is to only demonstrate to you content that corresponds to your interests. Advertisements which are unlikely to be of interest to you or which are irrelevant will not be shown to you by the activated behavioral targeting system of LiquidM and will be disabled.

In such a case, this section IV. of the data protection declaration applies as part of the respective web-based services of our partners or customers, from which (for example under “data protection” or “data protection declaration” direct reference was made or a link was created. We wish to disclose to you in a transparent manner how the behavioral targeting works, which data is gathered in the process, how this data is used and for what purpose and how you can object to the behavioral targeting function at any time and block it.

As a German/European company, the protection of your data is a priority for LiquidM, also in the course of the delivery of behavior-based advertising and LiquidM only uses anonymized data to improve advert quality. Therefore, an identification of your person is not possible either for LiquidM or the respective operator of the website of our partners and customers which you are visiting. You can yourself decide at any time whether you would like to continue seeing the personalized banner from LiquidM.

**a) How does behavioral targeting work in individual cases?**

We take part in a programmatic auction system where placements for advertisement in apps and websites are sold. In this process, we may collect information about you and your use of the website or app. This information cannot be used to identify you in real life but it does enable us to recognize your device when you use sites or apps that have partnered with us.

Another way we may deliver personalized advertising to you is when you visit the website of one of our partners or customers. On some of these sites, a cookie file is stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files which are deposited by your web browser in a folder on your computer which is designated for this purposes and which contains a single character string as a means of identification. (The cookie does not store your IP address.) The same character string is also saved on our servers. The next time you visit one of our partners’ websites, only the character string is read which identifies the Internet browser you are using. This allows us, for example, to identify which page you have accessed for our partner and which advert you have been shown, without this being linked to your identity. Furthermore, all of the cookies created by us are given an expiry data and automatically expire after no more than 13 months. Without a valid cookie file, the character strong saved on our servers is no longer to be assigned for us.

**Important:** Using cookies we cannot ever collect any other personal data. For example, when you enter an email address or delivery address, or any other personal data, we cannot see your input and cannot, therefore, process or store it. We do not know your name, address or workplace, nor do we know your gender, age, email address or any other personally identifiable information about you. Even the IP address of your computer is not stored! You can view the data stored in the cookie on your computer. Please refer to your web browser’s help directory or your web browser’s FAQ to learn how cookies are stored and how to read their content. The information contained within the cookie is the exact data that we can see Cookie technology does not allow viruses, trojans or other harmful programs to be placed on your computer.

A full list of the cookies used by LiquidM and their individual functions can be downloaded [here](https://liquidm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/LiquidM_Cookie_Documentation.pdf) at any time. Should you not agree to the saving of cookies on our part, you can examine your cookie status at the very top of this page at any time, and also deactivate the saving of behavioral targeting cookies by us. Therefore you can object to the personalized adverts from LiquidM at any time.

**b) How can I disable personalized advertising from LiquidM banners?**

If you do not agree to the storing of cookies by us, you can check your cookie status at any time at the very top of this page and disable the storage of retargeting cookies by us and therefore decline personalized adverts from LiquidM.

This means that in future you will receive random advertising that is not targeted to your interests.

Please note that the “opt-out” and “opt-in” functions offered are, for technical reasons, also controlled via cookies. This means that deleting all cookies on your computer means that you will have to opt-out again.

It is also the case that the deletion of all cookies on your computer does not lead to no personalized advertising being notified to you on a permanent basis. Therefore, you must use the  “opt-out” function as described.

Finally, please note that we are continuously expanding our range of products. As this will technically involve a new system, the introduction of a new opt-out may be necessary, even if you have already opted prior to its introduction.

**c) Can other forms of personalized advertising be disabled in addition to LiquidM?**

The options described in this section refer only to the personalized adverts offered by LiquidM. If you wish to disable personalized advertising from other providers, you can do this via their respective websites.

There is an option to change your settings collectively for various providers under preference management on “Your Online Choices”: _[http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/)_.

If you want to opt-out from the usage of the Advertising ID, please refer to your operating system settings, or follow the instructions below:

Android Users (version 2.3 and above) To use the “opt-out of interest-based advertising” option, follow the instructions provided by Google here: [_Google Play Help_](https://support.google.com/googleplay/answer/3405269).

iOS users (version 6 and above) To use the “Limit Ad-Tracking” option, follow the instructions provided by Apple here: [_Apple Support Center_](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4228)

Please note that these are device settings and will disable interest-based ads from all providers, and not just for us

**d) We also collect information about the advertisements that have been served to you by LiquidM and match them we the Advertising ID from the programmatic buying process.**

Information about the ads can contain:

* the details of the ad delivered (e.g. advertiser’s name, type of advert, etc);
* the website or the app where the ad was delivered;
* your interaction with the ad (i.e. whether you clicked, hid, muted or otherwise interacted with the ad);
* whether you performed certain actions after clicking on the ad (e.g. downloading an application, making a purchase, etc).

**e)** **How do we use the collected information?**

We use the information we collect to display interest-based advertising customized to individuals’ inferred interests, preferences and locations, and to perform analysis aimed at improving our services and technologies. We also need the information in the billing process with our customers and to validate the billings we receive from our partners. The information we collect also helps us to provide filtering options for publishers and developers to manage ads appearing on their sites and in their apps, and to provide targeting options for advertisers. In the end, this helps publishers and developer clients, for example, not to present you ads that you have already seen, and helps our advertiser clients serve adverts that are most likely to be of interest to you.

**Important:** We do not store the IP-Addresses un-anonymized or the Geographic location

**f)** **LiquidM and Google Authorized Buyers Program**

As part of the Google Authorized Buyers Program, LiquidM has agreed to adhere to the following [Program guidelines](https://www.google.com/doubleclick/adxbuyer/guidelines/). We highly encourage you to learn more about how Google’s products use data from sites and apps that use their services from the following partner-facing [documentation](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). For more information, please consult Google’s [Platform program policies](https://support.google.com/platformspolicy/answer/3013851?visit_id=637467333192867461-1496001747&hl=en&rd=1).

**IV. ANONYMOUS DATA/USE OF COOKIES**

We also use cookies on the LiquidM websites. Cookies are small text files, stored by your web browser in a dedicated directory on your computer or mobile device. Cookies are solely used to identify your web browser in an anonymous manner. Our cookie files only contain automatically generated ID numbers and a time stamp. We neither know your name, the place you live or work nor do we know your gender, your age, your e-mail address or any other similar information about you. The IP address of your device will also not be stored. You can view the data stored in the cookie on your computer. Please refer to your web browser’s help directory to learn how cookies are managed. The information contained within the cookie is the exact data that we can see Cookie technology does not allow viruses, trojans or other malware to be placed on your computer.

You can also use our websites without the use of cookies enabled. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. You can disable the storage of cookies or set your browser to notify you before accepting the storage of cookies. Please note that users who do not accept the storage of cookies may not be able to access certain functionality of our websites, or can only use our websites with considerable difficulty.

Further information and a full list of the cookies which are used by LiquidM on its own websites or on those of customers or partners, as well as their individual functions, can be downloaded [here](https://liquidm.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/LiquidM_Cookie_Documentation.pdf) at any time. In addition, you can generally prevent the storing of cookies by adjusting your browser settings accordingly.

**V. LEGAL BASIS**

The legal bases for the processing of your data could be the following:

* Your consent to the use of data in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. a) GDPR;
* The performance of our service obligations arising from contracts concluded with you in order to provide the services you request in accordance with Article 6 (1) lit. (b) GDPR;
* Our legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. f) GDPR, e. g. 
    * Our business interests in improving our services so that we can better understand your needs and expectations and thus improve the services we provide to you;
    * To prevent fraud and to ensure that our websites are used completely and without any fraudulent behavior;
    * To ensure and guarantee the security of our services, making sure that our offer is technically secure and properly functioning;
    * to ensure and enforce our contractual requirements and claims.
* Legal reasons in accordance with Art. 6 (1) lit. c) GDPR if the collection, storage, transfer or other processing of data is prescribed by law or processing is necessary to fulfill our legal obligations.

**VI. DATA STORAGE**

We store personal information you submit to us only for as long as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which such information was transmitted, or as required by law:

* If you conclude contracts with us, we store and process your personal data for the duration of the contractual relationship and beyond for the fulfillment of post-contractual obligations and handling of issues as well as for the duration of statutory retention periods (maximum 10 years);
* If you have consented to the promotional use of your e-mail address, we will store your e-mail address with our mail service provider until you unsubscribe, requesting us to delete the data;
* If you send us an inquiry, we process your personal data while we handle your request.

**VII. IS PERSONAL INFORMATION FORWARDED TO THIRD PARTIES?**

We forward your Advertising ID  we received from our Partners to companies running the advertising campaigns on our service or companies providing anonymous audience data in case we register that you saw one of our advertisements or in case you clicked on an advertisement. This is only done for billing and statistical reasons. In certain cases, we are also required by law to disclose your personal information to third parties. This is, for example, the case when the suspicion of a criminal offense or a misuse of our websites occurs. We are then required to disclose your data to law enforcement authorities.

Outside of the cases described in this data protection declaration, your data is not forwarded on to third parties and, your information is solely stored in our databases / on our servers (or on the servers of third-party providers).

**VIII. HYPERLINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

In addition, our websites contain hyperlinks to websites offered by third parties When clicked, the hyperlinks redirect you from our website directly to the website of another provider. You can recognize this redirection process by the change of the URL in your web browser’s address bar. If you have been forwarded to the website of a cooperation or promotional partner, the use of your personal information will only be subject to the privacy policy of the relevant provider. We cannot take any responsibility for the privacy practices of third parties´ websites because we do have no control over their compliance with data protection regulations.

**IX. PROTECTION OF MINORS**

Persons under 18 years are excluded from our services and from providing any personal information without the consent of their parents or guardians. We do not request personal information from children and adolescents. We do not knowingly gather or collect such data and do not disclose it to third parties.

**X. HOW WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION SECURE**

When we collect information, we solely store your data on highly protected servers in Germany and the EU. Access to our IT infrastructure is strictly limited to authorized persons who are involved in the technical, commercial or editorial support.

In order to avoid loss or misuse of data stored by us, we have taken all necessary and extensive technical and organizational safety precautions, which are regularly checked and updated based on technological advancements in accordance to the GDPR.

However, we would like to inform you that because of the nature of the Internet, the provisions of data protection and data security measures described in this Privacy Policy may not be observed by any third parties or institutions beyond our control. Especially unencrypted data transmission – even when sent via e-mail – can be read by third parties. We have no technical influence on this. The user has the responsibility to protect the information he provides from misuse by encryption, selection of a secure password or other means.

**XI. RIGHTS OF THE “DATA SUBJECT” ACCORDING TO THE RULES OF THE GDPR:**

According to the EU General Data Protection Regulation, you deserve the right to request access to your personal data (see Art. 15), as well as rectification (see Art. 16), erasure (see Art. 17) or at least restriction of processing (see Art. 18) of your personal data.

Furthermore, you have a right to data portability (see Art. 20) and, of course, the right to revoke any consent given to the processing of personal data at any time (see Art. 7) and to object to processing based on the balancing of legitimate interests (see Art. 21(4) GDPR). In addition, you have a right to appeal to the competent data protection supervisory authority.

If you have any questions or other feedback on the subject of data protection or would like to exercise your rights regarding data protection, please contact our Data Protection Officer or ourselves:

Rechtsanwalt Stephan Krämer, LL.M.,

Kinast & Partner Rechtsanwälte

LiquidM Technology GmbH

Invalidenstr. 74

10557 Berlin

Germany

E-Mail: [privacy@liquidm.com](mailto:privacy@liquidm.com)

* * *

Version: May 2018 – We reserve the right to adapt this data protection declaration and will announce any changes in good time.

#### Navigation

#### Legal Information

#### Newsletter

Leave this field empty if you're human: 

© 2020 by LiquidM Technology
